一旦我们有了模板,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Once
we have the template,
我们可以定义组件来使用查询。
we can define component to use the query.
这样就会得到这个查询的结果作为数据。
And so that is gonna get
the result of this query as data.
盖茨比在建造过程中的工作方式
So the way that Gatsby works during
the build is it's gonna look for
这个导出的查询。
this exported query.
它实际上会执行它，得到数据,
And it will actually execute it,
get the data,
然后将这些数据作为数据支撑注入到这个组件中。
and then inject that data as
a data prop to this component.
这些都是在构建过程中完成的。
This is all done during the build.
这是一个重写的过程。
So there's kind of a rewrite process.
同样，保持这些模板分离的另一个原因是
Again, another reason to keep
these templates separate so
很明显他们得到了特殊处理。
that it's clear that they
get special handling.
然后这些数据会被放在某个地方。
That data then is going
to be put somewhere.
我想做的是直接将它传递给将要使用它的组件。
And what I like to do is just pass it
directly to a component that will use it.
所以我要这么做。
And so I'm just gonna do that.
我直接去数据库看看 docspage 可以进去了。
I'm gonna go straight into
the data.docsPage, can go in.
现在我们必须定义它。
And now we have to define that.
但首先，让我们出口这个 DocsPage。
But first, let's export this DocsPage.
我们得把这个医生页面弄出来。
Okay, so we're gonna need to
go get this this docs page.
我要把它放在组件里，我们称之为文档页。 Js.
I'm gonna put it in components,
we'll call it docs-page.js.
在这个里面，我们要从‘ react’进口 react。
And inside of this one,
we're going to import react from 'react'.
我们将导入 MDXRenderer。
We will import the MDXRenderer.
Mdxrenderer 实际上用于将其转换成可读的内容。
And the MDXRenderer is used to actually
make this into something readable.
所以所有这些 MDX 生成的代码，我们希望能够使用它
So all of these code that MDX generates,
we wanna be able to use it and
Mdxrenderer 为我们提供了这种可能。
the MDXRenderer makes that possible for
us.
我还要调出我们用过的布局。
I'm also gonna pull in
the layout that we used.
让我来开门。
So let me get that.
然后，我们可以做一个 DocsPage 组件。
And then, we can do a DocsPage component.
我们将把这个布局放在这里。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We will
then put this layout in here.
1，Do page.title and then put in
Do an h1, do page.title and then put in
2.1.1.1.1.2.1.2.1.2.1.2.2.1.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2.2
the MDXRenderer,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: page.body
进到里面。
goes inside of that.
然后我们在底部放一张小纸条，上面写着这一页
And then we'll put a little note at
the bottom that says this page was
更新，Jason Lengstorf: 每当更新
updated,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Whenever the updated
价值是。
value is.
再说一次，这是很简单的语言，所以我们可以直接把它放到句子里。
And again, it's plain language so we can
just drop it right into the sentence.
所以我们要导出默认的 DocsPage。
So we're gonna export default DocsPage.
然后我可以保存它，回到这里，让我们导入这个
And then I can save that,
come back here and let's import this so
我们可以利用它。
that we can use it.
从... / components / docs-page 导入 DocsPage。
import DocsPage from
.../components/ docs-page.
现在，如果我停下来
And now, if I stop and
重新启动，在我们停止和重新启动，我们需要实际使用这些模板。
restart, before we stop and restart,
we need to actually use these templates.
所以我们已经定义了它们，但是现在我们需要运行 Create Page API 钩子。
So we've defined them but now we need
to run the Create Page API hook.
回到我们的盖茨比节点，一直到底部。
So back in our Gatsby node,
all the way down at the bottom here.
我们要用 exports.createPages。
We're going to use exports.createPages.
因为我们要求提供数据,
And because we're gonna make a request for
data,
我们把它标记为异步函数。
we're gonna mark this
as an async function.
创建页面 API 给我们提供了一些东西。
And the create pages API
gives us a few things.
第一个是一个 actions 对象，它给我们提供了一系列辅助函数。
The first is an actions object that
gives us a bunch of helper functions.
一个 graphql 函数，允许我们获取一些数据。
A graphql function that'll
allow us to get some data.
然后我们还有一个记者，如果我们想帮助把任何东西
And then we also have a reporter in case
we want to help put anything to the to
控制台。
the console.
第二个论点是主题中的选项。
And then the second argument is
gonna be the options from the theme.
所以，詹森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们不是真的
So,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We're not really
利用这些选项。
using the options.
所以我想，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 跳过这个。
So I'm gonna just,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Skip that actually.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们会得到一个充满动作的对象,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So
we're gonna get an object full of actions,
graphql 功能和记者功能。
the graphql function and
a reporter function.
然后在内部，我们从获取数据开始，所以我们要做一个 graphql 查询。
And then inside, we start out by getting
our data, so we wanna do a graphql query.
在 createPages 内部，graphql 是一个函数，而不是模板标记。
And inside the createPages,
graphql is a function, not a template tag.
刚开始的时候，这有点让人捉摸不透。
That's a little bit of
a gotcha at the beginning.
在里面，我要得到所有的 DocsPages，我想要所有的节点。
And inside, I'm gonna get all
the DocsPages and I want all the nodes.
我在这里需要的就是身份和路径。
And all I need in here is the id and
the path.
所以在这个上下文中，我要用来传递的 id。
So the id,
I'm gonna use to pass in this context.
这个路径，我将用作 URL 的定义。
And the path,
I'm gonna use as definition for the URL.
所以我们一直在等待这个结果。
So we've awaited that result.
然后我们要做个快速检查看看有没有什么问题。
And then we're just gonna do a quick
check to see if anything wrong.
因此，如果结果错误，我们将会恐慌。
So, if result.errors, we will panic.
所以我要做记者恐慌我们会说装载文件时出错,
So I'll do reporter.panic and
we'll say error loading docs,
然后把错误传过去。
and just pass in the errors.
如果我们度过了这个难关，我们就可以假设一切正常。
If we get through that,
we can assume everything's okay.
因此，只要抓住我们的网页，潜入我们的数据在这里。
So just grab out our pages by
diving into our data here.
所以我们要做 result.data.allDocsPages.nodes。
So we'll do
result.data.allDocsPages.nodes.
然后一旦我们得到了这些页面，我们就可以循环遍历它们。
And then once we've got those pages,
we can loop through them.
所以我们要做一个 forEach，因为我们不返回任何东西。
So we'll do a forEach because
we're not returning anything.
在 forEach 页面中，我们将运行一个名为 createPage 的操作。
And forEach page, we're going to
run an action called createPage.
接受一个有两个必填字段的对象
And that accepts an object which
has two required fields and
一个可选字段，我们要用到。
one optional field that we're gonna use.
第一个必需的字段是 path。
The first required field is path.
为此，我们将使用页面路径。
And for that,
we're gonna use the page path.
这也是我们希望用基本路径定义的,
And that's again what we desire
defined using the base path,
相对目录，然后是文件名。
the relative directory and
then the file name.
接下来，我们需要给它一个组件
Next, we need to give it a component and
这个分量就是我们刚才定义的模板。
that component is gonna be
the template that we just defined.
因此，我们将做一个要求点解决，进入我们的源模板和
So we'll do a require dot resolve,
go into our source templates and
文档页面模板。
the docs page template.
最后，我们需要设定一些背景。
And finally we need to set some context.
上下文是一个对象，这是任意的，我们可以放任何我们想要的东西。
And the context is an object, this is
arbitrary, we can put whatever we want.
有一些保留的字段，但大多数情况下，应该没问题。
There are a few reserved fields but
for the most part, it should be okay.
在上下文中，如果您使用保留字段，您将得到一个很大的警告。
In the context, you'll get a big
warning if you use a reserved field.
所以在上下文中，我要通过这个 pageID
So in the context,
I'm gonna pass in this pageID and
我希望那是 page.id。
I want that to be the page.id.
不管我现在给它取什么名字，它都会变成一个 graphql 变量。
And whatever name I give it now, it will
become available as a graphql variable.
我们在这里定义了 pageID。
So, we defined in here, pageID.
因此，通过在上下文中定义 pageID，我们就能够访问它。
So by defining pageID in the context,
we're able to access it.
现在，一旦我们做到了这一点，我们就，祈祷，准备摇滚起来。
Now once we've done this, we are,
fingers crossed, ready to rock and roll.
那么，让我们来构建一些页面。
So let's build some pages.
很有希望。
That's promising.
我们得到了两页。
We're getting two pages.
让我们来看看。
And let's give it a look.
我们走吧。
Hey, there we go.
现在，我们有了自己的主页。
So now, we've got our homepage.
它显示 MDX 内容。
It shows the MDX content.
它显示了我们的布局，也显示了页面更新的时间。
It shows our layout, and
it shows us when the page was updated.
这意味着我们得到了数据,
So that means that we've
got data coming in,
通过 Gatsby 的数据层进行定制，现在已经出现在屏幕上了。
getting customized through Gatsby's
data layer and now is on the screen.
所以这是非常强大的，对吧？
So this is pretty powerful, right?
我们现在状态很好。
We're in pretty good shape here.
所以我们接下来要做的就是
So our next move here, is going to be
让它看起来不那么可怕，并且更具可扩展性。
to make this look slightly less terrible
and in a way that's more extensible.
怎么了？
What's up?
演讲者2: 为什么印了两页？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Why did
it put out two pages?
我以为只有一个 MDX 文件。
I thought it was only the one MDX file.
Jason Lengstorf: 所以，只有一个 MDX 文件,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So,
there's only the one MDX file,
但是盖茨比总是会给你404页。
but Gatsby will always
give you a 404 page.
所以，如果我们去一个页面，我没有禁用。
So, if we go to a page
that I haven't disabled.
如果我们去一个不存在的页面，所以
If we go to a page that doesn't exist, so
让我启动它，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 它会的
let me boot this up,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: It will
还有这404页。
also give us this 404 page.
这是第二个被引用的页面。
So this is the page that's being
referenced as the second one.
这在开发过程中是一件非常好的事情，因为特别是如果
And that's a really nice thing to have
during development because especially if
你还没有设置导航系统
you haven't set up your navigation or
然而，你可以得到的点，你已经创建了一堆网页，但
something yet, you can get to the point
where you've created a bunch of pages but
你还没有列出清单给他们看。
you haven't built the list
to show them all.
这个会给你那个名单。
Well this will give you that list.
所以这是一个很好的小方便的东西，当你仍然在进行和
So it's a nice little convenience thing
to have when you're still in progress and
事情在不同的变化阶段，以确保你不会忘记链接
things are kinda in various stages of flux
to make sure that you don't forget to link
某些页面。
to certain pages.
演讲者2: 那么你是在导出页面查询,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So
were you exporting the page queries,
还需要导出到静态查询吗？
do you need that export to
static queries as well?
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 不，所以
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: No, so
页面查询是我们向盖茨比表示的特殊情况
the the page query is our special case
where we are signifying to Gatsby
在构建过程中，特别是在创建页面。
that during the build process
specifically during on create pages.
这个模板将被使用，并且这个查询应该被视为一个页面查询,
This template is gonna be used, and this
query should be treated as a page query,
这使得它可以访问上下文，就像变量之类的东西。
that gives it access to the context which
is the like the variables and stuff.
在静态查询中。
In a static query.
静态查询就是
A static query is just any use of
组件内部的 usestatic 查询将被提取。
usestatic query inside of
a component will be picked up.
但是这里的限制仍然是我们不能使用变量。
But again the limitation here
is that we can't use variables.
我们无法了解外部环境。
There's is no access to outside context.
我们甚至可以添加一个数据，我不能采取一个道具和
We can even interpolate a data,
I couldn't take a prop and
那就把道具放在这里。
then put that prop in here.
因此，静态查询需要在构建时进行硬编码。
So a static query needs to
be hard coded at build time.
原因就在于盖茨比处理图层的方式
And the reason for that is that the way
that gatsby's handling the graphql layer
在引擎盖下，一旦网站建成，graphql 层就不能继续工作了。
under the hood, that graphql layer doesn't
continue to work once the site is built.
它只是在那里，在建造和
It's only there during the built and
这意味着所有这些查询实际上都被编译走了。
that means that all of these queries
are actually getting compiled away.
这些都是通过抽象语法树转换完成的。
And that's being done using abstract
syntax tree transformations.
这就是巴别塔在引擎盖下的工作方式，它需要代码和
It's kinda how Babel works under the hood,
it takes the code and
它把它分解成组成部分和标记。
it breaks it into its component pieces and
tokens.
然后它可以理解这些作为一种编程语言。
And then it kind of understands
those as a programming language.
然后对 AST 进行修改。
And then the AST gets modified.
所以 Gatsby 将采用组件，寻找这些使用静态查询实例,
So Gatsby will take the component,
look for these use static query instances,
将其分解为 AST，用查询结果替换它，然后
break that down into an AST, replace
it with the results of the query, and
然后用适当的数据重写那个组件。
then rewrite that component
with the data in place.
这就是为什么有限制的原因，因为当你进入
So that's why there are restrictions
on it because when you get into
转换,
AST transformations,
追踪一个变量到它被声明的地方是很有挑战性的。
trying to chase down a variable to where
it's declared is really challenging.
这是团队正在努力解决的问题，但还没有到位。
That is something that the team is
working on but it is not in place yet.
议长2: 他想知道我们是否只能输出一页的文件或者
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: He wants to know if we can
export only one page brief on page file or
可以导出多个查询。
you can export multiple queries.
每个页面文件只能导出一个查询。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: You can only
export one query per page file.
但这实际上不是一个问题。
But that actually isn't a problem.
因为您可以随心所欲地在每个查询之间添加任意多的查询。
Because you can just add as many
queries as you want next to each other.
它就是 data.docspage data.allfile。
And it would just be
data.docspage data.allfile.
所以你只能做一个查询，但是
So you can only do one query, but
这个查询可以有任意多的子查询。
that query can have as many
sub queries in it as you want.